Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we have a very exciting elementary lesson for you.
今天我们为大家准备了一节非常精彩的基础课程。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to take our clothes to the dry cleaners.
我们要把衣服送到干洗店去。
Okay.
好的。
So that means we have some dirty clothes.
也就是说我们有一些脏衣服。
They need to be cleaned.
它们需要清洗。
Let's listen to this dialogue one time and when we come back, we'll be talking about
我们先听一遍这段对话，等回来之后，
the words and phrases that you hear in it.
我们会讨论里面出现的单词和短语。
Thank God you're open.
谢天谢地你还开着门。
I have an emergency.
我有急事。
Hello Mr. Henderson.
你好，Henderson先生。
What can I do for you?
我能为您做什么？
I need this dress and this suit dry cleaned ASAP.
我需要这件裙子和这套西装尽快干洗。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready by the end of the week.
我可以在周末前准备好。
No, you don't understand.
不，你不明白。
I need this tomorrow morning.
我明天早上就要。
I accidentally spilled beer all over my wife's dress and we have a wedding to attend tomorrow.
我不小心把啤酒洒在我妻子的裙子上，我们明天要去参加婚礼。
She's going to kill me.
她会杀了我的。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready tomorrow afternoon.
我可以在明天下午准备好。
But this suit is also very stained.
但这套西装也有很多污渍。
I can't guarantee we can remove it completely.
我不能保证能完全去除。
Fine.
好吧。
Can you also iron and starch this shirt?
你能顺便熨烫并上浆这件衬衫吗？
Certainly.
当然可以。
Great.
太好了。
This is our secret.
这是我们之间的秘密。
If you see my wife, say nothing to her about this.
如果你见到我妻子，什么都别跟她说。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now there are probably a couple of words that you didn't understand so why don't we look
现在可能有一些单词你们没听懂，所以我们来看看
at those now in Language Takeaway.
语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Marco, you already told our listeners about one phrase, to dry clean.
Marco，你已经跟听众们提过一个短语了，就是“干洗”。
So dry cleaned.
所以是“干洗过的”。
Alright so that's when you take your clothes to a professional who doesn't only wash them,
好的，那就是你把衣服交给专业人士，他们不只是洗衣服，
right?
对吧？
You don't just put water and soap on it.
你不仅仅是用水和肥皂。
They actually put some special chemicals and use special machines to get very hard to remove
他们实际上会用一些特殊的化学品和机器来处理很难去除的
stains from it.
污渍。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is often what we use when we clean coats or fancy shirts and dresses because
所以这通常是我们清洗外套、高档衬衫和裙子时用的方法，因为
you don't want to clean those yourself.
你不想自己洗这些。
Right.
对。
You can't put those in the washing machine.
你不能把它们放进洗衣机。
No.
不能。
So this is the dry cleaner.
所以这就是干洗店。
That's the name of the place.
那是这个地方的名字。
And the action, what they do is they dry clean clothes.
而动作，他们做的就是干洗衣服。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Alright.
好的。
So we take them to the dry cleaners because we want to remove stains.
所以我们把衣服送到干洗店，因为想去除污渍。
Okay.
好的。
So a stain is a mark or some color that does not come off, does not go away.
所以污渍就是一块痕迹或颜色，去不掉，消失不了。
Alright.
好的。
So for example, sometimes you can have a wine stain.
比如，有时候你会有红酒渍。
Oh, wine stains are the worst.
哦，红酒渍是最糟糕的。
They're red and they never come off.
它们是红色的，永远去不掉。
Or blood stain.
或者血渍。
Oh.
哦。
Right.
对。
So a stain is a noun but you can also use it as an adjective.
所以污渍是名词，但也可以用作形容词。
My shirt is stained.
我的衬衫有污渍了。
Okay.
好的。
So it's stained.
所以它是有污渍的。
My pants are stained and I can't wear them again.
我的裤子有污渍了，不能再穿了。
Again, you can also use it as a verb.
同样，你也可以把它用作动词。
I stained my pants.
我弄脏了我的裤子。
Alright.
好的。
So it's a verb, it's a noun and an adjective all in one.
所以它既是动词，又是名词和形容词。
Easy to remember.
容易记住。
Well, there's another word that's related to this word.
嗯，还有一个跟这个词相关的词。
We spilled something.
我们洒了什么东西。
Okay.
好的。
So I spilled wine and it stained my shirt.
所以我洒了红酒，弄脏了我的衬衫。
Okay.
好的。
So to spill and that means that you took some liquid and you put it onto your clothes.
所以“洒”意思是你不小心把液体弄到衣服上。
Or you dropped it and it made a mess.
或者你把它掉下来，弄得一团糟。
Okay.
好的。
So spill.
所以是“洒”。
I spilled some milk.
我洒了一些牛奶。
Okay.
好的。
Spilled.
洒了。
Now it's pronounced differently from spell, right?
现在它的发音和“拼写”不一样，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Spill.
洒。
It has an I, spilled.
它有一个I，洒了。
Alright.
好的。
Now our next word is also a noun and a verb.
现在我们的下一个词也是名词和动词。
To iron.
熨烫。
To iron means to make something flat with no lines.
熨烫意思是把东西弄平，没有褶皱。
Okay.
好的。
To smooth it out.
把它弄平整。
So we use an iron to iron.
所以我们用熨斗来熨烫。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a metal electronic object.
它是一个金属电子物品。
It gets very hot.
它会变得很热。
So you wash your shirts for example and your shirts are wrinkled because you just washed
比如你洗了衬衫，衬衫是皱的，因为你刚洗过
them.
它们。
So you need to iron them.
所以你需要熨烫它们。
That's right.
没错。
So you smooth them out, you flatten them with this object, an iron.
所以你用这个叫熨斗的东西把它们弄平、弄平整。
Okay.
好的。
And well, usually if you take them to the dry cleaners, they will iron them and also
嗯，通常如果你把衣服送到干洗店，他们会熨烫，还会
starch them.
上浆。
Okay.
好的。
To starch something means to use some powder or chemical to make something stiff or hard.
上浆意思是使用一些粉末或化学品让东西变硬或挺括。
So the noun or the chemical is also called starch.
所以名词或化学品也叫淀粉。
Exactly.
没错。
So you think of a shirt with many buttons that a man wears to work.
所以想象一件男士上班穿的有很多纽扣的衬衫。
He has a collar around his neck and that needs to be high and tall.
他脖子上有领子，需要立起来、挺起来。
It can't be flat and wrinkled.
不能是扁塌塌、皱巴巴的。
And so a dry cleaner will use starch to make sure that this stands up.
所以干洗店会用淀粉来确保领子立起来。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So those are five key words for the dialogue today.
所以这些就是今天对话中的五个关键词。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
让我们再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
Thank God you're open.
谢天谢地你还开着门。
I have an emergency.
我有急事。
Hello, Mr. Henderson.
你好，亨德森先生。
What can I do for you?
我能为您做些什么？
I need this dress and this suit dry cleaned ASAP.
我需要尽快干洗这条裙子和这套西装。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready by the end of the week.
我可以在周末前准备好。
No, you don't understand.
不，你不明白。
I need this tomorrow morning.
我明天早上就要。
I accidentally spilled beer all over my wife's dress and we have a wedding to attend tomorrow.
我不小心把啤酒洒在我妻子的裙子上了，我们明天要参加一个婚礼。
She's going to kill me.
她会杀了我的。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready tomorrow afternoon, but this suit is also very stained.
我可以在明天下午准备好，但这套西装也沾了很多污渍。
I can't guarantee we can remove it completely.
我不能保证能完全去除。
Fine.
好吧。
Can you also iron and starch this shirt?
你能顺便熨烫并上浆这件衬衫吗？
Certainly.
当然可以。
Great.
太好了。
This is our secret.
这是我们之间的秘密。
If you see my wife, say nothing to her about this.
如果你见到我妻子，什么都别跟她说。
All right.
好的。
We're back now.
我们回来了。
So let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
那么让我们来看看流利度训练。
Thank God.
谢天谢地。
All right.
好的。
What is this phrase?
这个短语是什么意思？
Thank God.
谢天谢地。
Okay.
好的。
This is a phrase we use in English to say that we're happy about something or that we're
这是英语中用来表达我们对某事感到高兴或
relieved.
松了一口气的短语。
Okay.
好的。
So maybe I'm nervous that the mail isn't going to come today.
所以也许我担心邮件今天不会来。
Then the mail comes and I say, oh, thank God the mail came.
然后邮件来了，我说，哦，谢天谢地邮件来了。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm happy.
我很高兴。
I was hoping it would come.
我本来希望它能来。
So you're relieved.
所以你松了一口气。
Thank God.
谢天谢地。
Now, we are using the word there, God, but it doesn't really have a religious connotation
现在我们用了“God”这个词，但它其实没有宗教含义。
that much, right?
没那么重，对吧？
Not anymore.
现在不这么用了。
No.
对。
It's usually just a phrase.
它通常只是一个短语。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Now what about this acronym ASAP or ASAP?
那这个缩写ASAP或ASAP呢？
ASAP.
ASAP。
So as soon as possible.
就是“as soon as possible”的意思。
It's an acronym.
这是一个首字母缩写。
So the first letter comes from the word.
所以第一个字母来自单词。
It means as soon as possible, very quickly, right away.
意思是尽快、非常快、立刻。
You always hear that in an office setting as well.
你在办公室环境里也经常听到。
I need those papers ASAP.
我急需那些文件，ASAP。
I need those reports ASAP.
我急需那些报告，ASAP。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can say it either way, ASAP or ASAP and it means immediately.
所以你可以两种方式说，ASAP或ASAP，意思都是立即。
Okay.
好的。
And he said that he needed the suit ASAP and he said, I can have it ready by the end of
他说他需要那套西装ASAP，然后他说我可以在周末前准备好。
the week.
周末前。
Okay, so that might not be fast enough for the client, for the person here who has the
好的，所以对于有污渍的客户来说，这可能不够快，但“周末前”是一个非常非常有用的短语，因为它意味着也许今天是周一或周二，到周五或周六，我们就能为你准备好。
stain, but the end of the week is a very, very useful phrase because it means that maybe
因为我们通常把周末想成周五，也许是周四、周五。
today's Monday or Tuesday, by Friday or Saturday, we'll have this ready for you.
所以我可以说是“周末前”或“今天结束前”。
Because we think of the end of the week as Friday, maybe Thursday, Friday.
没错。
So I can say the end of the week or the end of the day.
“月底前”。
Exactly.
或者“年底前”。
The end of the month.
没错。
Or the end of the year.
所以“...结束前”通常指的是最后的时间点。
Exactly.
所以谢天谢地，这周结束了。
So the end of is usually the last time.
我准备好过周末了。
So thank goodness it's the end of the week.
非常好。
I'm ready for my weekend.
好的。
Very good.
那里也有很棒的短语。
Okay.
让我们最后听一遍对话。
So great phrases there as well.
谢天谢地你还开着门。
Let's listen to the dialogue for the last time.
我有急事。
Thank God you are open.
谢天谢地你还开着门。
I have an emergency.
我有急事。
Hello Mr. Henderson.
你好，亨德森先生。
What can I do for you?
我能为您做些什么？
I need this dress and this suit dry cleaned ASAP.
我需要尽快干洗这条裙子和这套西装。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready by the end of the week.
我可以在周末前准备好。
No, you don't understand.
不，你没明白。
I need this tomorrow morning.
我明天早上就要。
I accidentally spilled beer all over my wife's dress and we have a wedding to attend tomorrow.
我不小心把啤酒洒在我妻子的裙子上，我们明天要参加一个婚礼。
She's going to kill me.
她会杀了我的。
Okay.
好的。
I can have it ready tomorrow afternoon, but this suit is also very stained.
我可以在明天下午准备好，但这套西装也沾了很多污渍。
I can't guarantee we can remove it completely.
我不能保证能完全去除。
Fine.
好吧。
Can you also iron and starch this shirt?
你能顺便熨烫并上浆这件衬衫吗？
Certainly.
当然可以。
Great.
太好了。
This is our secret.
这是我们之间的秘密。
If you see my wife, say nothing to her about this.
如果你见到我妻子，什么都别说。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now dry cleaning, ironing.
所以现在聊干洗、熨烫。
Are you good at this or do you get a lot of your clothes dry cleaned?
你擅长这个吗，还是你经常把衣服送去干洗？
I'm pretty good at this actually.
其实我挺擅长的。
I don't like to wash clothes.
我不喜欢洗衣服。
I get really bored with the washing machine, but I actually really like ironing.
用洗衣机洗衣服让我觉得很无聊，但我其实很喜欢熨烫。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
I find it very relaxing.
我觉得熨烫很放松。
Really?
真的吗？
I find it very frustrating.
我觉得熨烫很让人沮丧。
Really?
真的吗？
Why is that?
为什么？
Because I can't really iron well because I start on one side and I'm getting all the
因为我熨得不好，我从一边开始把所有的
lines out and then the other side gets wrinkled or lines appear where I don't want them to
褶皱弄平，然后另一边又起皱，或者出现我不想有的
appear.
褶皱。
It's very frustrating for me.
这让我很沮丧。
It is frustrating.
确实让人沮丧。
It takes some practice.
这需要一些练习。
My suggestion is to use the spritzer.
我的建议是使用喷雾器。
In the iron, there's some water that can come out like that.
熨斗里有一些水可以像那样喷出来。
Well, if you spray the water, it makes the lines go out for longer.
嗯，如果你喷水，可以让褶皱消失得更久。
Because if you iron over that, it's more permanent.
因为如果你熨烫过那个地方，它会变得更持久。
I've also seen some sprays sometimes that you can spray your clothes with some special
我还见过一些喷雾，有时你可以用它们喷在衣服上，喷上一些特殊的
chemical that's not actually starch, but it helps remove the wrinkles quicker.
化学物质，其实不是淀粉，但能帮助更快地去除皱纹。
Exactly.
没错。
I don't use that.
我不用那个。
I use water generally, but they're all available.
我一般用水，但它们都有卖的。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the time we have for today.
这就是我们今天的所有时间了。
If you have any questions or comments, you can visit our comment section on EnglishPod.com
如果你有任何问题或评论，可以访问我们EnglishPod.com的评论区，
and we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Bye.
再见。